MORDECAI JUNIOR MATHENGE

PERSONAL INFO

Phone: 0774471681 or 0115588218 E-mail: <u>mathengemordecai@gmail.com</u>

GitHub: github.com/morde2002

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mordecai-mathenge-b097bb1b5

Portfolio: https://morde2002.github.io/mordecaiportfolio.github.io



OBJECTIVE

I am a confident, high-driven student in Information and Technology with knowledge on computer Maintenance, troubleshooting and 5 years' experience in developing and testing of enterprise software Applications as a java, HTML, C and CSS programmer. Resourceful and proactive, I apply detailed technology knowledge to identify and troubleshooting IT Issues and deliver a satisfactory outcome for the company whilst working alone and as part of a larger Team. I am currently looking for an opportunity to further my career within the IT sector.



EDUCATION

Diploma in Information and Technology | Mount Kenya University

JAN 2021 - APRIL 2023

I have successfully completed my university diploma with an Honors designation, achieving a credit 1.



EXPERIENCE

Information and Technology | Kenya Petroleum Refineries Limited 12th JAN 2023 – 12th APRIL 2023

Attachment.

Duties and Responsibilities

- Installation, configuration and maintaining computer systems.
- Email support, setting up new users' accounts, profiles and updating email signatures.
- Troubleshooting system and network problems, diagnosing and solving hardware or software
- Faults and replacing parts as required.
- Supporting the SUN, e-horizon, SAP and LIMS system.
- Establishing a good working relationship with colleagues, KPRL staff and other outside Professionals such as Software Developers.
- Proactively assist in backup and recovery operations by assisting in maintaining and monitoring Backup equipment and data.

- ICT manager to keep track of ICT inventory.
- Software installation and customization.
- Hardware management including replacement of computer parts, blowing of machines and troubleshooting for hardware problems.
- Provide helpdesk and technical support either by phone, remote access or site visits.

Information and Technology | ICT Authority

24th JUNE 2023 – 21st SEPTEMBER

Attachment.

Duties and Responsibilities

- Networking and website design.
- Network operator for Uhuru na Kazi building.
- Maintenance and support of ICT systems
- Supervision of replacing worn out networking equipment by the contractors.
- Maintenance of server room ground floor Uhuru Na Kazi Building
- Assist with help desk calls, scheduling, and tickets management
- Follow up on user requests and ensure timely resolution
- Under IT staff guidance, create accounts and configure end-user computer systems
- Assist in the maintenance of IT standards and documentation
- Maintain audio and video equipment in conference rooms
- Support / maintenance of IP telephony system



PROJECT

BASKETBALL TEAM WEBSITE

Individual project

- Link to my website: (https://morde2002.github.io/pworkcn.github.io/)
- Developed an online basketball registration website for registering new members or team players
- Using html, CSS and JavaScript. Provided value to basketball players who wish to join the well-known basketball team.

BARAKA MINING & MINERALS LTD WEBSITE

Group project

- Link to our website: (https://barakaminingltd.co.ke)
- The Baraka Mining and Minerals website is a dynamic and forward-thinking mining and minerals company that specializes in the exploration and extraction of precious gemstones from around the world. The company prides itself on its commitment to ethical and sustainable practices, ensuring that each gemstone they offer reflects not only exceptional beauty but also responsible sourcing.

• This website represents not only a marketplace but a testament to the dedication of Baraka Mining company to offer the finest gemstones while upholding the highest standards of ethics and sustainability.

TEXOL ENERGY COMPANY UGANDA WEBSITE

Individual project

- Link to the website: (https://morde2002.github.io/texol2.github.io)
- Texol Energies Uganda is a prominent player in Uganda's oil and gas industry. Established in 2022, the company has rapidly become a leading provider of energy solutions in the region. Texol Energies stands out for its commitment to excellence, offering high-quality petroleum products and services. With a strong presence in Kampala and beyond, Texol Energies is known for its reliable fuel supply, eco-conscious practices, and a customer-centric approach. The company's focus on innovation and environmental responsibility positions it as a key contributor to Uganda's energy landscape, driving progress and empowering communities.



SKILLS

Experience in:

- C, C++ and C#|ASP.NET.
- HTML5|CSS|Bootstrap 4.
- Java and JavaScript.

- PHP and SQL.
- Node.js, React.js and Three.js.
- Data Science and Machine Learning.

Exposure to:

- SQL | Microsoft SQL Management Studio
- Git| GitHub
- Microsoft Azure

General skills:

- Ability to work independently as well as in team Environment.
- Excellent communication and presentation Skills.
- General knowledge with Microsoft Office Application.
- Familiarity with windows desktop and server Operating system.
- Able to work in a fast-paced environment.

...

··· ACTIVITIES/HOBBIES

- Programming
- Designing websites, games etc.
- Swimming

- Reading
- Playing basketball leagues
- Listening to music



Mr. Samuel Macharia Mwangi smmwangi@mku.ac.ke
ICT coordinator

Mount Kenya University Mombasa, Kenya 0700575653

Arcad Mkoji Arcad.Mkoji@kprl.co.ke

Head Of IT Department (H. O. D Manager) Kenya Petroleum Refineries Limited Mombasa, Kenya 0722840330 Linus Nyongesa

Linus.Nyongesa@kprl.co.ke

System Administrator

Kenya Petroleum Refineries Limited

Mombasa, Kenya 0701164550

Engineer Tony Otieno Ajode

tony.ajode@ict.go.ke

Head Of ICT Coast Region Co-Ordinator

ICT Authority

Mombasa, Kenya 0711915529